Guide to the Thomas Rogers Forbes Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Thomas Rogers Forbes papers
1925-1989
MS 913
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
12
The Forbes papers document Thomas Rogers Forbes's professional life, predominantly his years at Yale University. The materials include correspondence, subject files and items associated with his administrative responsibilities and editorial and committee work. Research and writings files highlight his scientific research on hormones, as well as his publications and films in the history of medicine.
Forbes, Thomas Rogers, 1911-1988
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Thomas R. Forbes, 1979, 1982, and 1985; gift of Helen A. (Mrs. Thomas R.) Forbes, 1989 and 1991; and transferred from the School of Medicine, 1990.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Thomas Rogers Forbes was born in New York City on January 5, 1911. He earned both his 1933 bachelor's degree and his 1937 doctorate at the University of Rochester. Forbes taught anatomy at Johns Hopkins University, 1937-1942. During World War II, he interrupted his teaching to serve on the Committee on Medical Research of the Office of Scientific Research and Development. In 1945, he was appointed instructor in anatomy at the Yale School of Medicine. He served as an assistant professor from 1946 to 1951, associate professor from 1951-1962, and attained the rank of professor in 1962. He served concurrently as assistant and then associate dean from 1948 to 1969, while also chairing the Committee on Admissions. Forbes was appointed Ebenezer K. Hunt Professor of Anatomy in 1977. In 1979, he became professor emeritus and senior research scholar in the history of medicine.
Forbes made fundamental contributions to reproductive endocrinology as a scientist and also won recognition as a medical historian. With Charles W. Hooker in 1946, Forbes developed an accurate method to measure minute quantities of progesterone. The Hooker Forbes bioassay became a standard method in endocrinology. Over the next thirty years, Forbes and his collaborators contributed substantially to the understanding of progesterone's role in pregnancy. His scholarly achievements included several books on early English forensic medicine. His books on early medical jurisprudence reflect personalities, as well as the standards of expertise then extant in the field. Forbes was an innovative teacher, producing films to teach medical history to students.
He married Helen Frances Allen in 1934. They had two sons, Thomas R. Jr., and William M. Thomas Rogers Forbes died in Branford, Connecticut on November 13, 1988.
Scope and Contents
The Forbes papers document Thomas Rogers Forbes's professional life, predominantly his years at Yale University. The materials include correspondence, subject files and items associated with his administrative responsibilities and editorial and committee work. Research and writings files highlight his scientific research on hormones, as well as his publications and films in the history of medicine.
Arrangement
Arranged in three series: Series I. General Files, 1925-1988. Series II. Teaching, Research, and Writings, 1930-1989. Series III. Personal Papers, 1930s-1988.
Journal of the history of medicine and allied sciences; Hormones; Progesterone; Forbes, Thomas Rogers, 1911-1988; Hooker, Charles Wright, 1910-; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University. School of Medicine
- Correspondence, 1925-1988; Series I
  Scope and Contents
  The series includes correspondence and other papers that document Forbes's professional activities and acquaintances. There are few family letters. The files of greatest substance focus on Forbes's administrative and committee work at Yale and his participation in a medical mission for the Unitarian Service Committee.
  The files are in two sequences following Forbes's own designation: an alphabetical arrangement by the name of an individual, institution, or journal, and a chronological file. The files include incoming and outgoing letters with colleagues, students, suppliers, institutions, and journals, including the Journal of the History of Medicine and Allied Sciences. The Yale material, which is arranged by department or unit, includes documents associated with Forbes's responsibilities within the Department of Anatomy, the Dean's Office, the Admissions Committee, the History of Medicine Department, and the Medical School Council, and as advisor on medical memorabilia. The Unitarian Service Committee files detail Forbes's 1950 trip to lecture to German medical students and physicians whose learning and work had been interrupted by World War II. These files also include correspondence in the years following Forbes's return to the United States.
  - Academic Press [London], 1980-1985 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1951-1982 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - American Association for the History of Medicine, 1953-1988 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - American Association of Anatomists
    - General, 1938, 1965-1985 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Committee on Anatomical Nomenclature, 1970-1975 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - American Philosophical Society
    - General, 1970-1988 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Verbal Charms in Folk Medicine", 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - American Society of Zoologists, 1959-1974 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Atheneum [London], 1982-1987 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Baue, Arthur, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Beaumont Medical Club of Connecticut, 1947-1988 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Bell, Whitfield J., Jr., 1974-1985, undated. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Benfey, Bruno, 1950-1955 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Bishop, Peter, [195?]-1979 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Boving, Bent G., 1951-1958 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Brigham Young University, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Bynum, William, 1971-1988 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Chatterton, Robert, 1969-1977 (Box 2, Folder 18 - 19)
  - Collison-Baxter, G. L., 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Commonwealth Club, 1941-1942 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Connecticut Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1965-1987 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Cooper, Christopher, R. H., 1974-1984 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Corner, George W., 1937-1981, undated. (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Corporation of London, Records Office, 1970-1984 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Darling, George B., 1945-1971 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Early English Forensic Medicine [exhibit], 1987 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Emmens, C. W., 1953 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Encyclopedia of American Popular Beliefs and Superstitions, 1980-1987 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Endocrine Society, 1949-1986 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Excerpta Medica, 1946-1949 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Foley, S. John, 1953-1970 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Forbes family, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Frank, Julia, 1974-1977 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Fulton, John F. and Lucia, 1942-1962 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Gardner, Lytt
    General note
    See Box 19, Folder 61
  - Goodman, Gerri, 1983-1985, undated. (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Gorlin, Jed, 1981-1984, undated. (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Gormsen, Harald, 1950-1964, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Great Britain. Public Record Office Library, 1972-1978, undated. (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Greater London Council. Greater London Record Office, 1972-1983 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Greenwald, Gary and Maria White, 1977-1985 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Grolier, Inc., 1963-1978 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Guildhall Library, 1964-1986 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Hadisumarto, Willy, 1954-1955 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Hair, P. E. H., 1974 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Hartman, Carl G., 1945-1948, 1963-1967, undated. (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Harvester Microform, 1984-1986 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Havard, John D. J., 1986 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Hollaender, Albert E. J., 1970-1987 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Hooker, Charles W., 1948-1976 (Box 3, Folder 50 - 51)
  - Hunnisett, Roy, 1973-1988 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Hyde, Ralph, 1980-1982, undated. (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - International Society for the History of Medicine, 1976-1986 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Johns Hopkins University, 1937-1945 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Jost, Alfred, 1949-1962, undated. (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Journal of the History of Medicine and Allied Sciences, 1951-1984 (Box 4, Folder 57 - 60)
  - Joy, Robert J. T., 1976-1987 (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Kapadia, Shanta, 1974-1985 (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Kaufmann, C., 1955-1958 (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Keele, Kenneth D., 1960-1987 (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Keller, Deane, 1963-1977 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Klein, Irmhild, 1952-1958, undated (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - Knapman, Paul A., 1984-1986 (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - Korevaar, Wilhelmina, 1975-1977 (Box 5, Folder 68)
  - Lehrann, Daniel
    See: Box 19, Folder 62
  - Leonardo da Vinci Society, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 69)
  - London Topographical Society, 1972-1979, undated. (Box 5, Folder 70)
  - Mant, A. Keith, 1977-1988 (Box 5, Folder 71)
  - Massey, Robert, 1987-1988 (Box 5, Folder 72)
  - National Board of Medical Examiners, 1947-1951 (Box 5, Folder 73)
  - National Institutes of Health. Special Study Section [history], 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 74)
  - National Research Council. Division of Medical Sciences, 1945-1947 (Box 5, Folder 75)
    See also: Box 20, Folders 82-83
  - National Science Foundation [evaluations of proposals], 1956-1962 (Box 5, Folder 76)
  - Nu Sigma Society, 1968-1969 (Box 5, Folder 77)
  - Oppenheimer, Ernst, 1953-1960 (Box 5, Folder 78)
  - Parkes, Alan S., 1938-1940, 1955-1961 (Box 5, Folder 79)
  - Paul, David, 1976-1985 (Box 5, Folder 80)
  - Plotz, E. Jurgen, 1952-1953 (Box 5, Folder 81)
  - Pugh, Ralph, 1979-1982 (Box 5, Folder 82)
  - Random House, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 83)
  - Reilly, Phillip, 1978-1981 (Box 5, Folder 84)
  - Reynaud, Albert, 1958-1986 (Box 5, Folder 85)
  - Richards, Sarah [Mrs. Frederic], 1988 (Box 5, Folder 86)
  - Romm, Sharon [ Medical Heritage ], 1985-1988 (Box 5, Folder 87)
  - Royal Historical Society, 1982-1987 (Box 5, Folder 88)
  - Royal Society of Medicine, 1958-1988 (Box 5, Folder 89)
  - Rubinstein, Lidia, 1961-1969 (Box 5, Folder 90)
  - Sargent, Frederick, 1976-1978 (Box 5, Folder 91)
  - Schultz, Adolph H., 1939-1977 (Box 6, Folder 92)
  - Short, Roger, 1956-1971 (Box 6, Folder 93)
  - Simpson, Keith, 1982-1985 (Box 6, Folder 94)
  - Smith, Audrey, 1957-1959 (Box 6, Folder 95)
  - Society for Experimental Biology and Medicine, 1949-1985 (Box 6, Folder 96)
  - Society for the Social History of Medicine, 1970-1987 (Box 6, Folder 97)
  - Society of Antiquarians of London, 1980-1988 (Box 6, Folder 98)
  - Society of the Sigma Xi, 1964-1974 (Box 6, Folder 99)
  - Stevenson, Lloyd G., 1963-1967 (Box 6, Folder 100)
  - Strong, Felicity, 1974-1977 (Box 6, Folder 101)
  - Stroup, Nancy, 1980-1986 (Box 6, Folder 102)
  - Swarbrick, Margaret, 1971-1977 (Box 6, Folder 103)
  - Taku, Elaine and Fumio, 1978-1986 (Box 6, Folder 104)
  - Talbot, Charles, 1965-1986 (Box 6, Folder 105)
  - Taussig, Helen, 1981, undated. (Box 6, Folder 106)
  - Tell, Terry, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 107)
  - Telson, Howard, 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 108)
  - Temkin, Oswei, 1946-1979 (Box 6, Folder 109)
  - Textbooks, 1966-1981 (Box 6, Folder 110)
  - Thomson, Grethe, 1954-1955 (Box 6, Folder 111)
  - Tuchmann-Duplessis, Herbert, 1950-1987, undated. (Box 6, Folder 112)
  - UCLA Conference on American Folk Medicine, 1972-1976 (Box 7, Folder 113)
  - Unitarian Service Committee. Medical Mission to Germany, 1950-1960 (Box 7, Folder 114 - 118)
  - United States
    - Department of Agriculture, 1938-1942 (Box 7, Folder 119)
    - Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, 1962-1969 (Box 7, Folder 120)
    - Navy Department. Office of Chief of Navy Operations, 1937-1942 (Box 7, Folder 121)
  - University of Colorado Medical Center, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 122)
  - Veterans Administration, 1946-1949 (Box 8, Folder 123)
  - Vickers, H. M., 1938-1939, 1947-1948 (Box 8, Folder 124)
  - Wangensteen, Owen H., 1947, 1973-1978 (Box 8, Folder 125)
  - Watson, Neale, 1974-1981 (Box 8, Folder 126)
  - Weed, Lewis, 1945-1946 (Box 8, Folder 127)
  - Wellcome Institute of the History of Medicine, 1954-1982 (Box 8, Folder 128)
  - Wendt, G. G., 1966-1977 (Box 8, Folder 129)
  - Westphal, Ulrich
    See: Box 19, Folder 63
  - Westminster Abbey, 1973-1977 (Box 8, Folder 130)
  - Westminster City Library, 1972-1973 (Box 8, Folder 131)
  - Wiest, Walter
    See Box: Box 19, Folder 64
  - Williams, Stanley Thomas, 1953-1955, undated. (Box 8, Folder 132)
  - Wolstenholme, Gordon, 1950-1986 (Box 8, Folder 133 - 134)
  - Woody, Regina [Mrs. MacIver Woody], 1978-1983 (Box 8, Folder 135)
  - Worshipful Society of Apothecaries of London, 1960-1988 (Box 8, Folder 136)
  - Yale University
    - Branford College, 1954-1978 (Box 8, Folder 137)
    - Department of the History of Science and Medicine, 1952-1978 (Box 8, Folder 138)
    - School of Medicine
      - Advisor on medical memorabilia, 1949-1986 (Box 8, Folder 139)
      - Assistant and associate deanships, 1954-1971 (Box 8, Folder 140)
      - Committee on funds and fellowships, 1969-1973 (Box 8, Folder 141)
      - Committee on the future of the history of medicine at Yale, 1977-1978 (Box 8, Folder 142)
      - Department of Anatomy
        - General, 1945-1974 (Box 9, Folder 143 - 146)
        - Curriculum changes, 1959-1972 (Box 9, Folder 147)
        - Exhibits, history of anatomy, 1959-1980 (Box 9, Folder 148)
        - Laboratory, 1951-1985 (Box 9, Folder 149)
        - Library, 1946-1967 (Box 9, Folder 150)
      - Lippard, Vernon W., reception in honor of, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 151)
      - Medical Historical Library. Medical Print Project, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 152)
      - Medical Library Associates, 1970-1987 (Box 9, Folder 153)
      - Medical Library Committee, 1947-1978 (Box 9, Folder 154 - 155)
      - Section of Gross Anatomy, 1974-1980 (Box 9, Folder 156)
      - Stone, Leon Stanfield [portrait], 1961-1962 (Box 9, Folder 157)
      - Student statistics, 1945-1968 (Box 9, Folder 158)
      - Study group on student evaluation, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 159)
  - Yale University Press, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 160)
  - Young, James Harvey, 1978-1987 (Box 10, Folder 161)
  - Zander, Josef, 1954-1981 (Box 10, Folder 162 - 163)
  - Zarrow, M. X.
    See: Box 19, Folder 65
  - Chronological
    - 1925-1961 (Box 10, Folder 164 - 172)
    - 1962-1974 (Box 11, Folder 173 - 185)
    - 1975-1982 (Box 12, Folder 186 - 194)
    - 1983-1988, no date (Box 13, Folder 195 - 198)
- Teaching, Research, and Writings, 1930-1989; Series II
  The files in this series reflect Forbes's research interests both in the laboratory and in the field of medical history as well as his teaching in the class room. The teaching files, which include syllabi and lectures, are arranged chronologically by institution. They are predominantly from Yale, but include some earlier material from the University of Rochester and Johns Hopkins University
  The research materials contain laboratory notebooks and files concerning collaborations with students and colleagues, including Charles Hooker, in scientific research and writing. In the laboratory notebooks, experiments are labeled in sequences designated "series" by Forbes. Because he recorded a new series of experiments in a new notebook, even while an earlier series was still in progress, the notebooks are in overlapping chronological order. They include experiments on alligators, lizards, muskrats and progesterone. Research support from government and private agencies, as well as pharmaceutical companies, is also documented. Grant applications often provide partial bibliographies of Forbes's voluminous writings. These are useful, since no complete bibliography is available in the papers.
  The writings are arranged chronologically by type. Articles, both on laboratory research and on medical history comprise the bulk of the writings, but there are also files for books, films, abstracts, book reviews, lectures, and short stories. Experiments that were written up but not published are also included with the articles. The dates shown correspond to the dates of the material filed, not necessarily to the date of publication of the title.
  - Teaching
    - University of Rochester [histology outlines and bibliographies], 1934-1935 (Box 14, Folder 1 - 2)
    - Johns Hopkins University
      - Histology, 1937-1941 (Box 14, Folder 3 - 4)
      - Lectures [liver, testis], 1939-1941 (Box 14, Folder 5)
      - Neurology, 1939-1942 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Yale College [history of medicine lectures], 1977 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Yale School of Medicine
      - Administrative notes, 1947-1983 (Box 14, Folder 8)
      - Anatomy seminars, 1947-1967 (Box 14, Folder 9)
      - Derivations of some anatomical terms, 1970s (Box 14, Folder 10)
      - "Early History of Reproductive Endocrinology", 1984 (Box 14, Folder 11)
      - Endocrinology of reproduction, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 12)
      - Gross anatomy, 1946-1977 (Box 14, Folder 13)
      - Histology, 1945 (Box 14, Folder 14)
      - History of anatomy [lectures I-IV], 1930s-1988 (Box 14, Folder 15 - 16)
      - History of anatomy [lectures V-XVII], 1950s-1987 (Box 15, Folder 17 - 20)
      - History of anatomy [syllabus], 1949-1988 (Box 15, Folder 21)
      - Kidney [lecture], 1946 (Box 15, Folder 22)
      - Medical terminology, 1950s-1980s (Box 15, Folder 23)
      - Topographic and cross-section anatomy, 1949-1953 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Research
    - Laboratory notebooks
      - 1930-1934 (Box 15, Folder 25 - 26)
      - 1933-1953 (Box 16, Folder 27 - 36)
      - 1950-1970 (Box 17, Folder 37 - 44)
      - 1967-1971 (Box 18, Folder 45)
    - Laboratory supplies
      - Alligators, 1936-1940 (Box 18, Folder 46)
      - Cover slips, 1938-1947 (Box 18, Folder 47)
      - Equipment inventory, 1968-1969 (Box 18, Folder 48)
      - Lizards, 1938-1948 (Box 18, Folder 49)
    - Hormones
      - Ciba Pharmaceutical Products, Inc., 1941-1965 (Box 18, Folder 50)
      - G. D. Searle and Co., 1960 (Box 18, Folder 51)
      - National Biochemical Corporation, 1959-1973 (Box 18, Folder 52)
      - Radioactive compounds, 1955 (Box 18, Folder 53)
      - Schering Corporation, 1937-1963 (Box 18, Folder 54)
      - Squibb Institute, 1951-1966 (Box 18, Folder 55)
      - Upjohn Company, 1958-1971 (Box 18, Folder 56)
      - Wallace and Tiernan Products, Inc., 1941-1942 (Box 18, Folder 57)
      - Winthrop Chemical Company, 1941 (Box 18, Folder 58)
      - Various, 1936-1973 (Box 18, Folder 59)
    - Muskrat research, 1938-1941 (Box 18, Folder 60)
    - Progesterone research
      - Gardner, Lytt II, 1955-1959 (Box 19, Folder 61)
      - Lehrann, Daniel II, 1955-1956 (Box 19, Folder 62)
      - Westphal, Ulrich II, 1951-1971 (Box 19, Folder 63)
      - Wiest, Walter II, 1958-1972 (Box 19, Folder 64)
      - Zarrow, M. X. II., 1950-1956 (Box 19, Folder 65)
      - Other correspondence, 1948-1973 (Box 19, Folder 66 - 67)
    - Research grants
      - American Council of Learned Societies, 1964-1968 (Box 19, Folder 68)
      - Ciba Pharmaceutical Products, Inc., 1951 (Box 19, Folder 69)
      - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1941-1964 (Box 19, Folder 70)
      - National Institute of Child Health and Human Development, 1970-1971 (Box 19, Folder 71)
      - National Institutes of Health
        - 1949-1969 (Box 19, Folder 72 - 75)
        - 1972-1978 (Box 20, Folder 76 - 77)
      - National Library of Medicine, 1968-1987 (Box 20, Folder 78 - 81)
      - National Research Council II, 1944-1958 (Box 20, Folder 82 - 83)
      - National Science Foundation
        - 1958-1973 (Box 20, Folder 84 - 87)
        - 1974-1980 (Box 21, Folder 88)
      - Wellcome Trust, 1950-1959 (Box 21, Folder 89)
      - Withdrawn applications, 1949-1976 (Box 21, Folder 90 - 91)
      - Yale University, 1945-1952 (Box 21, Folder 92)
    - Student research, 1951-1975 (Box 21, Folder 93 - 94)
    - Unpublished experiments [series 50, 51, 57, 59], 1964 (Box 21, Folder 95)
  - Writings
    - Abstracts
      - Forbes's own papers, 1947-1973 (Box 21, Folder 96)
      - Excerpta Medica, 1947-1948 (Box 21, Folder 97)
    - Articles
      - "Studies on the Reproductive System of the Alligator, II: The Effects of Prolonged Injections of Oestrone in the Immature Alligator", 1938 (Box 21, Folder 98)
      - "Studies on the Reproductive System of the Alligator, V: The Effect of Injections of Testosterone Propionate on Immature Alligators", 1938-1939 (Box 21, Folder 99)
      - "A Note on Reptilian Sex Ratios" [unpublished], 1939 (Box 21, Folder 100)
      - "Observations on the Urogenital Anatomy of the Adult Male Lizard, Sceloporus, and the Action of Implanted Pellets of Testosterone and of Estrone", 1940 (Box 21, Folder 101)
      - "Studies on the Reproductive system of the Alligator, VI. Further Observations on the Heterosexual Structures in the Female Alligator", 1940 (Box 21, Folder 102)
      - "Absorption of Pellets...", 1941 (Box 22, Folder 103)
      - "The Origin of Freemartin", 1946 (Box 22, Folder 104)
      - "Testis Transplantation Performed by John Hunter", 1947 (Box 22, Folder 105)
      - "The Crowing Hen: Early Observations on Spontaneous Sex Reversal in Birds", 1947-1960 (Box 22, Folder 106)
      - "Education of Medical Students", 1948 (Box 22, Folder 107)
      - "Progesterone in the Blood Plasma of Cocks and Non-Ovulating Hens", 1949 (Box 22, Folder 108)
      - "A. A. Berthold and the First Endocrine Experiment: Some Speculation as to Its Origin", 1949-1950 (Box 22, Folder 109)
      - "Witch's Milk and Witch's Marks", 1949-1950 (Box 22, Folder 110)
      - Quelques Observations sur le Métabolisme et la Physiolgie du Progestérone, 1950 (Box 22, Folder 111)
      - "Systemic Plasma Progesterone During the Human Menstrual Cycle", 1950 (Box 22, Folder 112)
      - "Data on Relative Absorption Rates of Subcutaneous Pellets of Steroid Hormone in Rats", 1950-1951 (Box 22, Folder 113)
      - "Systemic Levels of Plasma Progesterone During Pregnancy in Women and Monkeys", 1951 (Box 22, Folder 114)
      - Quelques Données Récentes sur la Physiologie de la Progesterone [English translation], 1951-1953 (Box 22, Folder 115)
      - "Reproduction in the Female" [in A Textbook of Physiology ], 1951-1956 (Box 22, Folder 116)
      - "Progesterone in the Systemic Blood of Women and Monkeys During the Puerperium", 1952 (Box 22, Folder 117)
      - "Endocrinology" [in Encyclopedia Britannica Book of the Year ], 1952-1953 (Box 22, Folder 118)
      - "Levels of Progesterone in Systemic Plasma During the First Trimester of Human Pregnancy", 1953 (Box 22, Folder 119)
      - "The Origin of the Term Ridgeling"; "Pre-Ovulatory Progesterone in the Peripheral Blood of the Rabbit", 1953 (Box 22, Folder 120)
      - "Further Specificity Tests of a Bio-Assay for Progesterone", 1954 (Box 22, Folder 121)
      - "The Development of the Reproductive System of a Lizard, Anolis Carolinensis", 1954-1955 (Box 22, Folder 122)
      - "Student Fellowships Offer Unusual Opportunities", 1955 (Box 22, Folder 123)
      - "Plans Developing for New Residence Hall", [1955?] (Box 22, Folder 124)
      - "Plasma Progestin Levels in Progesterone Anesthesia", 1956 (Box 22, Folder 125)
      - "Δ4-3-Ketopregnene-20α-ol and Δ4-3-Ketopregnene-20β-ol, Two Naturally Occurring Metabolites of Progesterone..." [with Zander, Neher, and von Munstermann], 1957 (Box 22, Folder 126)
      - "Early Pregnancy and Fertility Tests", 1957 (Box 22, Folder 127)
      - "Progestin in Mouse Embryos, Placentae and Amniotic Fluid", 1957 (Box 22, Folder 128)
      - "Plasma Levels of Progestin During Pregnancy in the Mouse"[with C. W. Hooker], 1957-1958 (Box 22, Folder 129)
      - "Endocrinology of Reproduction in Cold-Blooded Vertebrates" [in Sex and Internal Secretions], 1957-1962 (Box 22, Folder 130)